

#### ROBOTICS ENGINEER

Via Antoniana 68. La Spezia, Italy

□ (+39) 329 404 2683 | 🗷 lucabonamini28@gmail.com | 🔏 lucabonamini.github.io | 🛅 luca-bonamini

## **Summary**\_

Luca Bonamini is currently a **Robotics Engineer** at **Proxima Robotics s.r.l.**. He received his Bachelor Degree in **Mechanical Engineering** from University of Genova and the Master Degree in **Robotics and Automation Engineering** from University of Pisa, in 2015 and 2018, respectively. After graduation he started a collaboration as Research Fellow at Robotics Research Center "E.Piaggio" of the University of Pisa, where he joined Roboteam-Italia, one of the teams of **Roborace**, an autonomous full scale electric racing car competition.

# Work Experience

Proxima Robotics s.r.l. Pisa, Italy

ROBOTICS ENGINEER Jan. 2019 - PRESENT

• Researching and developing software for mobile robots

Research Center "E. Piaggio"

Pisa, Italy

RESEARCH FELLOW Dec. 2018 - Jan. 2020

- Developed a lidar-based mapping and localisation system for autonomous racing cars
- · Worked as collaborator in Alter-Ego project

### **Education**

University of Pisa Pisa, Italy

M.S. IN ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION ENGINEERING

Sept. 2015 - Exp. Nov. 2018

• Towards a shared autonomy control framework: application to Ego robot navigation

University of Genova Genova, Italy

B.S. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Sept. 2012 - Sept. 2015

• Design of a two-stage parallel shaft gear reducer

#### Skills\_\_\_\_\_

**Programming** C/C++, Python, Matlab, HTML

**DevOps** Docker, GitLab CI/CD, Bash scripting

Tools GitLab, Git
Languages Italian, English

### **Publications**

#### **LiDAR-Based GNSS Denied Localization for Autonomous Racing Cars**

• Massa, F.; Bonamini, L.; Settimi, A.; Pallottino, L.; Caporale, D. Sensors 2020, 20, 3992.

### **Certifications**

1 First Certificate in English (FCE), Grade A, University of Cambridge ESOL Examinations

La Spezia, Italy